<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diego V Lakatos</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diego V Lakatos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s not always DNS, having fun with proxies, AWS IAM Roles and a pinch of Terraform</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aws-metada-service-with-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 12:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aws-metada-service-with-proxy/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While ago while working in a pipeline that was going to be used to create resources on AWS I faced a strange situation that led me to an interesting troubleshooting path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Diego Verissimo Lakatos and in this blog I expect to share my knowledge and also learn new things.
My areas of interests are cloud computing, containers, Linux and Infrastructure as code.
In my free time I like to read, watch movies and play video-games.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform to manage Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/using-terraform-to-manage-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/using-terraform-to-manage-kubernetes/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When working with kubernetes the standard way to create objects such as pods, deployments and services is to create a yaml manifest file that describes the desired state and then use &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; to create/update the object.
Althought, straightforward this process might create a barrier for developers and operations teams that now have to mantain a new codebase in a new &amp;ldquo;language&amp;rdquo;. YAML is easy to read but troubleshooting it might be difficult due the need for correct identation and the errors that are exibithed by &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt; might not be easily understood.
If a team is already using Terraform to create and manage the infrastructure it makes sense to use it to create the objects inside kubernetes as well, this brings some advantages such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
